CONTACT ME AT

ilquezada@mail.lipscomb.edu

www.linkedin.com/in/jlquezada

615-490-4600

https://github.com/Quezadajl

SKILLS

- Data Analysis
- Postgres SQL
- Python
- Tableau/PowerBI
- · Advanced Microsoft Excel functions (VLOOKUP)
- SAS

WORK EXPERIENCE

Middle School Math Teacher (6 years of Exp.)

Bedford County Public Schools DEC 2015 - MAY 2018

Franklin Special School District JUN 2018 - Currently

- Collaborated on the implementation hybrid learning environment.
- Small and large group presentation and Management.
- Fully certified with +300 hours of professional development

Data Analyst Apprenticeship

Lipscomb U./Nashville Software School || FEB 2021 - JAN 2022

- Assist with reporting of data quality.
- Collaborate with project leads and project managers to develop quality reports and dashboards.
- Identify areas where data quality improvements
- Demonstrated an understanding of analysis methods, design concepts, data organization, business models, and capabilities.
- Successfully applied statistical/data analytics concepts in practice applications of moderate difficulty.

JOSE L. QUEZADA

DATA ANALYST

PERSONAL PROFILE

I have thrived working alongside people with creative skillsets as a middle school math teacher for the past 7 years. Creating and managing student portfolios attracted me towards data analytics as it became my responsibility to instruct based on my student's performance. Data analytics in my classroom is what motivated me to expand on the world of analysis outside of education, expand my understanding of various tools and techniques to help individuals make decisions and succeed.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE DATA ANALYST

Nashville Software School July 2021 - January 2022

NSS is a six-month intensive, part-time data analytics bootcamp focusing on Excel, Postgre SQL, Tableau, PowerBI, and Python, including jobs such as data analyst, business analyst, research analyst, and marketing analyst.

- Create and document an analytics workflow using Python Notebooks.
- Use logic, conditionals, and formulas to create new data values using Spreadsheets.
- SQL querying, joining, and aggregating data, while looking at databases and dimensional models.
- Analytics workflow with Extract-Transform-Load processes.
- Communicating findings via storyboards, dashboards, and building reports using Tableau and PowerBI.
- Worked with Git and Github to manipulate projects, create and review pull requests and to resolve merge conflicts

PROJECTS

- Low Income and Elderly dashboard for trends using Microsoft Excel
- Collaborated with a small team of developers to create a dynamic dashboard application in Microsoft Excel analyzing trends in income.
- Demonstrated trends in scooter data from Metropolitan Nashville Public database using Python's Geospatial environment to map scooter usage.
- Applied the stages of ETL Extract-Transform-Load processes to create reports, pivot tables, functions, and formulas using Yelp data from Charlotte, NC.
- Used relational databases and dimensional models from Postgres SQL to assist a business by creating a report on possible partnerships.
- Created report visualizations using Tableau and PowerBI to communicate findings on Income among the Elderly population, and a superstore sales presentation.
- Created a storyboard using Python Jupyter Notebooks on GDP and internet use per country. Visualizations created with Seaborn libraries.
- Lead team towards success by offering structure and efficiency in project management using Kanban boards and daily stand-ups.

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY